Berta Romano Fernandez

High-energy human with loads to give. Former social worker, and now also an ex-Sommelier, making my way into a new industry with a new set of challenges where I can make an impact. I recently completed Google's Project Management course to expand my industry-specific vocabulary, learn new tools and gain an understanding of the life cycle of tech projects.

My extensive hospitality experience shaped me into a very adaptable and efficient person, a good listener who is able to juggle many moving pieces at once, with customers' happiness always a priority. A role in customer support in a tech company would be a great way to merge my recent learnings with my work experience. Put simply, I want to grow, keep busy and stay inspired.

KEY SKILLS

Interpersonal skills

- Years of customer service experience where I created long lasting relationships with guests and colleagues alike. While at Roux at Parliament Square, we received the UK wide Catey Award for Front of House Team of the Year (2017).
- Conducted training on new wines and wineries at team briefings to create stories for a more engaging guest experience while also providing information on off-the-list wines to help give a more dynamic and personalised service.

Adaptability

- Proven ability at adapting my communication style to a broad range of customers, stakeholders and colleagues.
- Continuous learning, as a Sommelier you can never know enough.
 Successfully completed two highly-regarded certifications in wine (AIS Sommelier and WSET Level 3) and built on that knowledge with daily readings, and attending trade tastings frequently.

Organisational skills

- Improved the Sommelier checklist by adding new responsibilities adapting to business' needs which led to improved employee accountability while reducing frustration and conflict among the team.
- Maximised efficiency by continuously re-organising wine cellars and fridges to adapt to ever-changing wine lists and stock levels and to ensure busy services ran smoothly.

Time management

Oversaw all restaurant sections during busy services to support teammates
with their tasks while maintaining close communication with the host to adhere
to table turn times, all while keeping high levels of customer satisfaction.

Problem solving

- Reduced accounting issues by creating and implementing a new stock transfer system within the different F&B outlets in the hotel, that improved cooperation and communication between teams.
- Dealt professionally with all sorts of customer complaints and queries in person and over the phone within the time constraints of a busy service, while also documenting the issues that arose and how they were resolved.

CONTACT

NW5, London 07989122309

bertaromanofernandez@gmail.com

EDUCATION

BA in Social Work Universitat de Barcelona, Spain

2007 - 2010

CERTIFICATES

Google Project

Management

Professional Certificate

Google - Coursera

Agile Project Management

Google - Coursera

Introduction to Business Management

Google - Coursera

LANGUAGES

English: Proficient Spanish: Native Catalan: Native

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Noble Rot, London — Sommelier

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JULY 2022

- Recommended and served wine in a refined fast-paced environment
- Managed the wine cellar inventory and daily wine list updates
- Helped hire and train new staff and led staff briefings
- Attended trade tastings to look for new additions to the wine list

Gymkhana, London — Sommelier

DECEMBER 2019 - JULY 2020

- Helped optimise processes before the restaurant reopened after a long closure
- Responsible for general cellar management and monthly stock take

Rosewood Hotel, London — Assistant Head Sommelier

JANUARY 2019 - JULY 2019

- Implemented a new stock transfer system within the different F&B outlets in the hotel
- Created wine training materials for the wider front of house staff
- Assisted the Event Operations team on bespoke events

Roux at Parliament Square, London — *Sommelier*

JUNE 2017 - AUGUST 2018

- Responsible for looking out for new wine additions to the wine list
- Created wine pairings for ever-changing tasting menus, bespoke private parties and catered events
- Acted as host when required, assigning tables, welcoming guests and taking phone reservations

Kenza Restaurant and Lounge, London — *Head Waitress*

AUGUST 2012 - FEBRUARY 2017

Souk Bazaar Restaurant, London — *Waitress*

JANUARY 2011 - AUGUST 2012

Social Care Services, Manresa (Spain) — *Social Worker*

AUGUST 2010 - DECEMBER 2010

- Case worker for people with disabilities serving the regional area, focused mainly on the rollout of the newly implemented social services law for "dependent" citizens
- Processed social services applications, conducted face to face client meetings and home visits, and referred clients to
 other services when needed, while offering emotional support and monitoring mental health
- Part of the regional coordination committee for disabled clients

CAP Sagrada Família (GP), Manresa (Spain) — *Medical Social Worker (Internship)*

OCTOBER 2009 - MAY 2010

- Assisted a social worker on her caseload, conducted appointments and home visits/checkups for GP patients
- Led weekly health related talk groups and took part on social work coordinating committee meetings
- Processed health related social services applications for vulnerable citizens and follow ups